Kane Maslen

WEB DEVELOPER

Career summary

I have a passion for creating user-centric mobile and web solutions with a strong background in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery and web frameworks such as AngularJS. My experience in graphic design coupled with my degree in Information Technology has allowed me to create, develop and implement a range of educational websites and applications for high profile clients such as ABC and SBS.

My ability to produce customised websites and applications using a best practice approach, combined with my desire to continue to learn and develop by utilising new and emerging technologies will be an asset to your company.

Work experience

International Education Services

Web Developer

Feb 2015 - Present

Working closely in a small, agile team I am responsible for the design, development and maintenance of a range of educational websites and applications.

- High level of proficiency with CSS, HTML and JavaScript including libraries and frameworks such as JQuery & AngularJS.
- Exceptional understanding of UI/UX, with the creative ability to produce conceptual designs, wire frames and prototypes to improve the experience of the end user and ensure scalability and consistency across screen sizes and devices.
- Experienced in mobile application development with several apps being released in both Google Play and Apple App stores.
- Experience with Bower, NPM, Grunt / Gulp and Git.
- Produce high quality designs for websites and mobile applications which include logos, icons and artwork produced with Illustrator and Photoshop.
- Investigating, fixing, and debugging software defects.

Stocks Appliances

Web Developer

Jan 2014 - Feb 2015

Website redesign and maintenance for development in WordPress, whilst implementing SEO strategies and campaigns.

Academic qualifications

2010 - 2014

Bachelor of Information Technology, Griffith University

GPA: 6.04 (Scale: 1 - 7)

Griffith Award for Academic Excellence 2013 & 2014

2002 - 2004

Diploma of Graphic Design, Morningside College of Art

Key Skills

Areas of expertise

- Creative flair
- Technical capability
- Deep UI/UX understanding
- Code quality
- Product vision

Web development skills

- Creating responsive user friendly websites and mobile applications.
- Front-End development with CSS and HTML and JavaScript expertise.
- Technical knowledge and experience with API's and creating dynamic experiences.
- Website and mobile application optimisation strategies and implementation.
- Conceptual designs, wire frames and prototyping.
- Expertise with Photoshop and Illustrator.
- Developing and enhancing new systems.
- Superb debugging and problem-solving skills.
- Understanding of the client/server model.
- Extensive Knowledge of databases, servers and operating systems.

Technical skills

- HTML CSS JavaScript SQL
- AngularJS ¡Query PHP Gulp
- MVC frameworks Drupal Git
- WordPress Illustrator NPM
- Photoshop Bower

Personal skills

- Innovative, enjoy looking for ways to improve the end product.
- Able to work independently or in a team.
- Clear and effective communication skills.
- Ability to follow complex instructions.
- Good time management skills and working to deadlines.
- Superior attention to detail.
- •Willing to go the 'extra mile' to get things done.

References

Available on request.

Contact details

Kane Maslen

10 Harraden ST, Oxley 4075

M: 0421 730 697

E: kanemaslen@gmail.com